# Louise Benson Junior Full Stack Developer

Louise.benson@gmail.com • +00353 87 6771703 • Dublin github.com/Louibens • linkedin.com/in/louise-benson-856792150/

# **Executive Summary**

Junior Software Developer currently studying for a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python. I have 20 years experience providing top class service to clients and colleagues in several industries, the majority of which have been online businesses. I have proven accuracy and attention to detail in my work and constantly strive to improve efficiency in tasks. I am eager to gain entry to the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

## Education

Currently studying Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

1999 – 2001 FETAC Certificate Multimedia & Web Design Certificate

**Bray Senior College** 

# Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Version Control: Git, Github, Heroku

# **Portfolio projects**

- Sustainability Ireland A website providing tips and advice for living a more sustainable lifestyle. Technologies Used - HTML5 and CSS. GitHub - <a href="https://github.com/Louibens/PP1-Sustainability Ireland">https://github.com/Louibens/PP1-Sustainability Ireland</a>
- 2. The World Quiz A quiz to test your world knowledge. Technologies Used HTML5, CSS and JavaScript. GitHub https://github.com/Louibens/PP2-The-World-Quiz

# **Work Experience**

2018 - 2020

## **Senior Partner Relationship Manager**

CarTrawler

- Managing approx. 10 online travel brands representing key accounts to optimise their use of CarTrawler products. Clients included Hotels.com, Finnair, Travel Republic and Expedia.
- Negotiating and securing prime real estate on client's websites to ensure the best

engagement with products.

- Weekly and Monthly reporting to clients and colleagues.
- Integrating new partners. Providing advise and best practise cases to secure prime positioning and product engagement. Assisting with technical issues and escalating to appropriate team where necessary.
- Liaising with partners and internal colleagues to resolve issues.
- Negotiation with client to ensure mutually beneficial contract renewals.
- Organising and running focus groups with clients.
- Data analysis of reporting to identify opportunities. For example, if reporting showed that a high level of requests for cars in a certain location were returning no results, this would be flagged to the supply team who could potentially engage with providers at that location to fill the gap.
- Working with partners on promotional campaigns. Providing advice on best practise and assisting with assets.
- Took responsibility for creating and maintaining training materials.

#### 2011 - 2018

#### CarTrawler

#### **Partner Relationship Manager**

- Managing a book of approx. 50 online travel brands to optimise their use of CarTrawler products.
- Negotiating and securing prime real estate on client's websites to ensure the best engagement with products.
- Weekly and Monthly reporting to clients and colleagues.
- Negotiating contract renewals.

#### 2010 - 2011

#### CarTrawler

#### **Customer Services Administrator**

- Resolving customer's post rental queries and complaints in line with targets by liaising with suppliers and internal departments
- Participating in company projects aiming to reduce the number of customer issues. Projects include reviewing the customer touch points to ensure information is clear for customers and liaising with suppliers to eliminate repeat issues.
- Communicating any issues to Data Entry to flag errors such as car category mismatches, incorrect/outdated supplier information, etc.
- Training new hires
- Cross trained to manage the partners mailbox.

2007 - 2009

MRQ Investments Ltd

PA / Office Administrator

2006 - 2007

CIT

**Customer Service, UK & Ireland** 

2004-2006 Needahotel.com

**Customer Service Agent** 

2004 - 8 mnth contract Diamond Furniture

**Customer Services** 

2001 - 2004 Dell Computers

**Customer Service Executive, Irish Relationship Department** 

# **Certifications**

• Key Account Management

- Project Management Foundations
- Advanced Excel
- Persuasion and negotiation

# **Interests/Additional Information**

- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Women in Tech I worked on design and front end development.
- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: World NGO Day I worked on front end dev.
- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Re:unify Forging connections with Code –
  Our team came 2<sup>nd</sup> in the Hackathon and was a great first experience entering a
  hackathon
- I attend regular 'women in tech' networking events.
- I'm a Cohort Lead in the CI Slack Community.
- I enjoy creating pieces using unwanted textiles with a strong focus on sustainable practices.